A short distance from New Delhi,
the country's capital,
this luxurious residence is preparing to host one of the most anticipated weddings of the year in the finest Indian tradition.
A multi-colored scene celebrating the alliance of two wealthy families of the textile industry before nearly 1,000 hand-picked guests.
The bridegroom wears the latest fashion accessory among the Indian Novel Rij,
a necklace of banknotes to assert power and prosperity.
Flashing his cash is the guest of honour's favourite activity.
This young bearded millionaire,
the bride's cousin,
Ivan Lutra,
defines himself as a serial internet entrepreneur.
He made a very substantial donation to the couple.
Definitely,
he's my brother and obviously yeah he did a lot of things.
I love him a lot.
Are you proud of all that he's doing?
Oh yeah,
definitely.
I'm so proud of him.
Very proud of him actually.
As soon as he takes a step now,
he distributes envelopes.
At the age of 22,
Evan claims to earn nearly a million euros a month and travels two-thirds of the year out of the country.
But he would not have missed the wedding for anything in the world.
I don't want to lose touch with my...
where I was brought up and...
where I grew up from.
That's what they say.
It doesn't matter how successful you get,
don't forget where you came from.
Indian weddings mostly go on for a long time,
usually at least a week with five or six functions.
And it means a lot.
It's a very excessive,
over-the-top affair.
So yeah,
I look forward to having a big,
fat Indian wedding.
So it's definitely something I enjoy for sure.
One foot in tradition,
the other in excess.
Tonight,
Evan has invited several foreign friends,
entrepreneurs and travellers like him.
They share photos and videos on social media for Ivan's fans.
The young man has hundreds of thousands of followers on Instagram.
This party is insane.
What I want to say,
Evan,
thank you that you have invited me to India.
It's one of my great best or best experiences I have in my life.
It was great to have you here,
no doubt.
Always welcome.
So,
we're going to keep partying and take you some drinks.
Woo-hoo All the way up,
guys.
OK,
let's go.
Yeah I can't do it.
You have to do it.
Steady,
come on.
Evan has a taste for parties,
luxury and money.
He embodies the brazen success of Indian businessmen who are eager to get rich.
In India,
they're known as the new Maharajas.
Rich,
praised by everyone,
megalomaniacs,
They have nothing to envy of their elders.
the old masters of India,
even if their style is radically different.
Since 2015,
India is third in the ranking of the world's billionaires behind the United States and China.
Thanks to the country's tremendous economic growth since the
2000s, there are four times more Indian billionaires today than 25 years ago.
The whole balance belongs to us.
Usually change my rooms when I come here.
While 400 million Indians live below the poverty line,
they bring together tradition and globalization with success and excess.
I'm trained for this,
that in our system,
you are trained to get into the family business and you expect it.
Gautam Singhania,
the descendant of an old family of merchants,
reigns over the Indian textile industry.
His fortune has multiplied by 10 in 10 years.
The champagne wishes and caviar dreams.
The Indian billionaires love expensive toys.
For Mr.
Neeta Mani's birthday,
they spent over 200 crores.
But in the country of Gandhi and Mother Teresa,
these insane expanses sometimes have a dark side,
especially since the country's masters are also tax evasion world champions.
India's most flamboyant,
a willful defaulter.
The king of alcohol,
Vijay Mallya,
opted for a golden exile to escape Texan prison.
We found him in England.
How come that you don't come home for face the justice of your country,
for example?
Why should I?
The revolution is that these masters of India are no longer just heirs.
This woman is a symbol of this,
Kalpanasa Rosh.
came from the caste of untouchables,
a marginalised community that lives in poverty.
Today,
she's the head of a real estate empire in Bombay.
It is a huge struggle to get this company.
I was able to do this struggle and get this.
This is also a history.
Who are these Indian businessmen and women who can't seem to be stopped?
What are their secrets?
For months we investigated the very elite circle of the new Maharajas.
Noida,
in the suburbs of Delhi.
Behind these gates,
this residential neighbourhood belongs to new Indian fortunes,
with secure grounds and private guards.
It is on the terrace of his parents'
house that we meet Ivan Lutra,
the young rich entrepreneur.
Fuck,
I don't know how to get it back.
Ivan is very busy with his new toy.
A state-of-the-art drone worth 2,000 euros.
Fuck,
don't ever fly it on the roof.
Is it broken?
I think it may be broken,
but you'll have to see when we try to fly it again.
It is in this luxury duplex with its breathtaking view of the capital.
that Ivan lived with his mother and father.
His family belonged to the Sikh community,
a religious minority known for its business acumen.
His father,
an entrepreneur,
made his fortune in the fashion and textile industry,
and this young man chose to follow in his footsteps very early on.
At the age of 12,
he created his first smartphone app.
He stopped his studies after high school to continue founding companies.
He summarises his goal in a series of figures.
These are goals that are set for myself,
that by 21 I will be making a million a month,
which I'm pretty close.
By
23rd I want to be at a million a week,
and by 25 a million a day.
As he aspires to become a billionaire,
the busy young man boldly displays his success.
As if to bring fortune,
Evan loves everything that shines and sees it as an investment.
I got it.
I love gold and black.
These are two of my colors,
which I really like.
So even I got this solid gold iPhone 7 made because I'm always on my phone.
I paid £10,000 for this,
but when I sell it,
it's probably going to sell for a lot more than £10,000 in a couple of years because it's just an asset.
Reptile skins are another of his weaknesses,
with a touch of gilding,
of course.
Yeah,
it's all Python.
It's kind of illegal in India to wear Python.
I could go to jail for this.
But I mean,
I'm pretty sure nobody really cares,
and there's a lot of people flooding this room in the open.
So yeah,
this bag is about $8,000.
But the thing is,
it doesn't lose its value.
I could sell this bag again,
probably would sell for a lot more,
especially because my initials on it now.
Arrival at the headquarters of the family business,
home to the young man's office.
The secret to Evan's success...
is the surge of services for mobile phones and cheap labor.
He has a team of computer specialists in the basement of the building,
all specializing in the creation of mobile apps.
This morning,
he is focused on improving a new project.
So what we're trying to do is we're trying to add a new feature.
We have already got the user login in the right.
We want to make a profile function for the user where the user can see his own profile and see which is his past bookings.
Can you give an estimate of how long it will take to build this out?
Around a month.
Bottlepop,
his very latest development,
targets the golden youth of large capitals.
Bottlepop is for tables and nightclubs.
Let's say if somebody wants to go out with their friends and they want to have a VIP table for themselves.
get a good service and they intend to spend money,
this app allows you to book a table with a click of a button.
To make more money quicker,
Ivan also buys ideas from others.
He has bought shares in several dozens of start-ups,
benefiting from some of their profits and watching his money grow.
My $90,000 that I invested is worth now over $2 million in that company.
So that's how I look at it.
and that's the
20x return instead of getting like
0.2x returns.
He got his entrepreneurial mindset from his father,
a fashion entrepreneur.
He is the one who provided Ivan with an initial investment to start him off.
This workshop produces clothing for American ready-to-wear.
At first skeptical,
Evan's father is now amazed by his son's lightning trajectory.
He is doing far better than we can imagine.
I would say like that.
At his age,
there are kids who even don't know what to do.
But he on his own,
he knows that he has an aim in life.
This is what I want to do.
While the son's success delights his father,
his spending is a different matter.
Religion and tradition hold an important place in his family.
a different generation,
different way of doing things.
Show-off is not a good thing.
Abroad it's fine because nobody is bothered.
In India,
today you buy a big car,
the person next door will say,
oh he's got a big car.
Last year,
he was out of India.
So fine,
at least 120 days that you are in India,
at least you can spend a couple of hours following your traditions.
The mother is always behind him.
At least follow some traditions.
Traditions will have to wait.
The young man is organizing his next trips to Europe and the United States,
where he will be able to satisfy his overindulgence.
The Indian Novorij,
love of glitz and glamour,
takes after the old masters of the country,
the real Maharajas,
whose wealth was measured by the splendor of their palaces.
Today still,
they own vast estates in Rajasthan,
the kingdom of the great Rajput families.
This is one of Rajasthan's most beautiful palaces.
which belongs to the Al-Ziza family.
Cousins of the Maharajas of the city of Jaipur,
the Al-Zizas have ruled over these lands for almost three centuries.
Now they're trying to preserve their royal lifestyles.
Nothing to do,
just bring the breakfast.
They'll just go quickly get the breakfast.
32-year-old Abhi Manju,
the eldest of the family,
always begins his day in the same way,
with silverware and waiters in uniform,
a meal at the foot of his bed with his younger brother.
If I go down and have breakfast,
then everybody's coming to meet you.
There's so much work happening,
and I hate that.
I feel your first meal should be in absolutely silence,
and only people you want to be with,
so that then you can plan your whole day,
what to do and when to do and how to do it.
Abhimanyu's father transformed the palace into a hotel 15 years ago,
entrusting its management to his eldest son.
Some 50 rooms at 150 euros on average.
Abhimanyu studied hotel management in some of the country's biggest palaces.
He is very picky.
I usually change my rooms when I come here.
Stay in a different room every time I come.
I believe in A,
there are a lot of advantages to it.
When people come to
Al-Sisar Mahal,
they should live those two days of their life,
of how I live.
That's the reason if you see the palace,
every room is absolutely different and showcases my life and my style and my passion for whatever I do.
The family promises a Maharaja's holiday,
but the maintenance of this
17th century palace costs a fortune,
especially since this young man wants only the best.
So this is the main Darbar Hall of the palace and this is where people used to come and meet my grandfather and you'll see all of them out there in paintings.
We've used in about 14,000 pieces of gold leaf to renovate this room back to its glory and it took me about a year to
finish this job.
for the gold leaf alone the family had to part with several tens of thousands of euros
To pay these vast bills and to differentiate themselves from other hotels set up by other aristocrats,
Abhimanyu came up with a rather wild idea,
to hold an electro music festival in his palace.
But first,
this morning,
several hundred people are at work.
The concerts begin in less than 24 hours in different areas of the palace.
This is the console from which magic is going to happen.
Nice,
not this stay the same.
What are you doing with the...
Slap back.
OK,
it's hitting here.
Oh,
nice.
The idea for the festival came to him with the help of a rock'n'roll star who is also a savvy businessman.
We were having a drink together with Babji,
me and Mick Jagger,
and Babji said that,
you know,
his father just recently gifted both the sons the main palace of Al-Sisa.
And so,
wow.
So he said,
oh,
you should do a festival there.
Shall we,
Dhruv?
A few hours before the arrival of the first festival goers,
Abhimanyu goes on an inspection tour in his jeep,
just like the ancient princes who visited their lands.
The prince asks young artists to decorate the village walls.
Beautiful,
beautiful.
The inauguration must be up to par.
3,000 music fans are expected,
mostly young,
trendy socialites from the capital,
who have spent more than 100 euros,
a significant sum in India.
We've pitched in about 700 tents this year,
and you have the palace right there.
The festival's reputation has reached beyond India's borders.
For its third edition,
some 40 DJs answered the prince's call,
coming from all over the world.
These two experimental artists arrive from Luxembourg.
The festival is just getting started.
We come across some French people in the crowd,
dazzled by Abimangu's hospitality.
Did you know the Prince before?
No,
not at all.
It's the Prince
It's a pleasure to meet you.
So he's the owner of the place?
Yes.
It's magical.
The place looks magical.
The place,
the decoration,
and the desert around.
It's completely that.
It's magnificent.
The prince's aim is to get people talking about Al-Ziza.
Today,
his goal has been achieved.
Music gives me an eye,
especially when it's playing at my home.
After all,
Al-Ziza is getting popular.
Mahal obviously comes along,
but the village is what needs to get popular.
The music-loving prince's next challenge is the organization of a traditional music festival in another of the family's palaces.
While the Indian kings were among the largest fortunes in the world at the beginning of the 20th century,
they must today make room for fortunes which started from nothing.
Descendants of the servant castes or even from untouchables,
the lowest caste in Indian society.
A fate that calls Slumdog Millionaire to mind.
In this village,
ten hours drive from Bombay,
most people live from the land,
in endemic poverty.
Yet it is here that one of the most incredible cases of social mobility in modern India began.
This village saw the birth of Kalpana Sarosh.
Today,
the head of the real estate empire worth 300 million euros.
Her father was a police officer and her family owned no land.
This is the house.
My relationship is that I was born here.
The only inhabitant of this mud hut is her
85-year-old aunt,
who doesn't want to leave despite her niece's wealth.
There is a clay stove and she burns wood to cook food.
She makes food for her own.
She doesn't want to depend on her daughter-in-law or son.
So she earns and eats her own food.
How is it?
It's good,
isn't it?
It's good.
Her return to the village may bring a crowd,
but Kalpana was born with an enormous handicap.
She grew up in a community that has always been marginalised,
the Untouchables.
This is the place where we can see the gutter.
This side is the place called Kunbipura.
This is Suvarnabha.
And this side is the place of the Buddhists.
In India,
the untouchables are the lowest in the Hindu social hierarchy.
A shunned population considered impure and confined to the most unpleasant jobs.
medical camp which offers free ophthalmological care and glasses.
The nearest hospital is a two-hour walk away from here.
Today is a real luxury for the villagers.
nations,
Kalpana takes care of everything.
A banquet is even served in a tent put up for the occasion.
The village takes on a festive air around the nation's child.
She even serves the meal herself.
We used to put mangoes or eggs in it and eat it.
MALCOLM BRABANT,
Kalpana Sarosh's story is one of a young girl who rebels against a destiny which was written for her.
Married at the age of 12,
she went to live in a slum and suffered violence from her in-laws.
Her father got her a divorce,
but her return to the village was difficult.
Even after coming here,
people couldn't tolerate girls coming here.
Even today,
it doesn't happen.
50 years ago,
there was no question.
40 years ago,
you understand.
People started talking about various things,
or doubting various things,
because of which I had to drink poison.
Then we thought,
okay,
it's fine.
We will do something to show the world.
And we started our journey.
So,
the coffee struggle started from then.
At the age of 16 Kalpana decided to leave for Bombay with some savings in her pocket and her only talents as a seamstress.
Working in a garment factory she patiently saved the small son.
She used it to buy a metal plant and invest in real estate.
Her first move was to buy a piece of life.
land in the north of the city.
She resold it at a premium price,
taking advantage of soaring
prices.
Kalpana,
whose audacity and courage have overcome prejudice and exclusion.
This is also one of India's secrets,
a country where everything's possible.
Although today she is the head of DBTP,
a powerful real estate and construction materials group,
Kalpana is against flashing wealth,
which she finds indecent given how she grew up.
It's from this modest office in the centre of Bombay that she continues her investments.
We will make it all in the same place.
And the one in the middle is a 150-room building.
It's not a 5-star building.
If we want to make it a 5-star building,
we don't have that much space.
We will give them
30 crore rupees.
We will make all this for them.
This is our heritage.
Kalpana works with her daughter Seema,
who graduated from a London university.
The
30-year-old has decided to follow in her mother's footsteps.
We have made it a bit stone-like.
Apart from business centres,
we have started a cafe.
People come here with their ideas.
They discuss their business ideas on coffee.
They give it to the investors.
Seema Saroj's project is the development of this building in downtown Bombay.
It's part of her mother's real estate.
The property's value is 120 million euros.
I think we have a plus point in our building that we can be able to see the documents there.
The VT station that side,
we have Taj the other round.
So I think it's amazing.
I think people will love to sit here and,
you know,
enjoy the evenings.
At the age of 30,
Seema's career as a businesswoman has already been laid out.
But unlike billionaire heirs,
Seema knows the sacrifices her mother had to make to get there.
I think she never,
me and my brother,
she never informed what is she facing or what is she going through.
She always showed us the happy,
loving mother,
never informed what all she has faced to achieve this.
And today,
when people like you come and take the interview from her,
interview we came to learn that how difficult it was for her to achieve all this.
Despite the multi-million dollar projects that they manage,
The Saroj family has not locked itself away in a bubble of luxury.
No grand apartments in chic neighborhoods.
The family live in this building in the northern suburb of the city.
On Sundays,
Kalpana entertains at her home in complete simplicity.
Her door stays open all day for family and neighbors,
but also for the poor who come to ask for her help.
This couple come from her village.
They have just travelled 15 hours by bus to inform her of the marriages of their two daughters.
50,000 rupees or nearly 700 euros.
For this family of farmers,
it's the equivalent of a year's income.
Tears of joy.
What will you do with this for your daughter?
Marry her.
We have to marry her.
We have to do it.
We have God.
We have
God. Do you want to know one more thing?
God.
No,
no,
he knows.
He's lying down.
Because of her origins,
Kalpana Saroj,
the philanthropist,
is an exception in the world of the Indian noble riche.
She has not yet reached the level of the highest fortunes,
which are worth billions.
Among these new tycoons,
everything is about excess,
and it's all part of the show.
Wide sandy beaches lined with coconut trees.
Goa,
on India's west coast,
is a playground for billionaires who want to escape the big cities for the weekend.
But however beautiful it may be,
when you are called Singhania,
the beach is too small.
It's a weekend with my school friends.
We do this once a year when all the friends who live abroad all come down.
Gautam Singhania is one of the most famous billionaires in India.
He manages the country's largest clothing brands.
At the age of 50,
the textile king's fortune is estimated at $1.5 billion.
When he goes away for the weekend,
it's on his yacht,
Ashina,
a
50-metre-long three-storey floating palace.
Built entirely out of precious wood,
he sails this luxury across the seas as and when he desires,
from the Indian Ocean to the Mediterranean.
Actually,
I enjoy taking the boat to the Maldives.
Maldives is beautiful,
but we haven't been in a long time,
but we'll probably get there soon.
The Sarkar Fran season is in July-August,
which is the best time,
and obviously we can't come to Goa at that time of the year because of the monsoon.
India's season is not there.
You've got to do a little bit of everything.
It's only 11am,
but the party has already started.
The weekend always begins with the chef's cocktail.
He's in a good mood.
He's put less water in.
I'm not going to waste so much.
Don't make it too strong.
It's not too strong.
The ice is cold.
Relax,
man.
MALCOLM BRABANT,
For these old school friends,
the weekend in Goa is a reunion not to be missed,
the breakfast especially.
The menu includes truffle omelet,
caviar,
Japanese chocolates and fine vintage wines.
The champagne wishes and caviar dreams.
30 years in the making.
Right,
Gautam?
About 40 years in the making,
42 years.
Something like that,
roughly.
Long years.
Gautama organised this trip himself and brought in goods from London by plane.
This weekend,
he opens the doors to his billionaire lifestyle to his closest friends.
This is Gautam's night luxury.
No,
he likes super luxury.
In what sense?
He's achieved what he has,
so he obviously wants the best,
best available wherever.
Whether it's Bombay,
Goa,
yes,
he loves luxury.
It's not easy to lead this lifestyle.
It's easy to say,
I wish I had a yacht or I wish I had an aircraft.
But I know a lot of the millionaires and billionaires.
I don't know many who do what he does.
By the end of the morning,
the group of
50-somethings have already fallen back into adolescence.
It is only the size and the style of the toys that has changed.
Goa has become the stomping ground of India's billionaires,
and that's because it is right next to their city,
Bombay.
The mega city,
with a population of over 20 million,
accounts for more than half of the country's super-rich.
Their latest whim?
is to have towers built in the heart of the city.
Some have been estimated at more than a billion euros.
These 37 stories,
which dominate the seafront,
are Guatama Singania's future residence.
The only part of the tower that has been built at the moment are these two levels,
dedicated to the family business,
textiles and their famous brand,
Raymond.
This company is a beast of 70 million euros of annual turnover,
60%
of market shares and 3,000 shops across the country.
Today,
the group's big boss inspects his brand's flagship.
How are your sales been?
Doing great,
sir.
We've done around 2 crore 11 lakh rupees.
Yesterday we finished our target.
For November?
Yes,
we've achieved 100%
sales.
Now how are your fabric sales going?
Amazingly well,
we've had a growth of around 45%
over the last year.
And new shirtings,
how are the new shirtings?
They've done really good and it's sold out.
two to three days.
Really?
The printed shirt,
especially.
That's very good.
The Raymond brand was launched by Gautama's family at the beginning of the
20th century.
It was losing momentum when he took his father's place in the CEO's chair in 2000.
The acclaimed company was in need for a dusting off,
a diversification.
Thanks to Gautama,
today,
Raymond is high-end and has increased in value.
So this would be about
3 lakh rupees a meter.
So a suit length would be about
14,000 euros for just the fabric for a suit.
And then the stitching,
etc.
Raymond is a brand,
you know,
it really sells from 250 euros.
...to 300,000 rupees a metre across the range.
And we say,
you know,
from the taxi driver to Mr Tata,
everybody wears the
Raymond brand.
In his stores,
the Indian textile boss wears a suit and tie.
But outside work,
he prefers sportswear.
That's because a day in the life of Gautama Singhania is a sprint from start to finish.
And to get around Bombay the quickest possible way,
he takes his helicopter.
The best way to avoid the traffic.
In the north of the city,
the company's headquarters.
A true American-style campus for the 1500 employees who work there.
Between royal palm trees and impeccable lawns.
Good to see you,
by the time you arrive.
Here,
the Singanias have reigned supreme since they bought the old wool factory in the
20th century.
So when the boss arrives to prepare a new collection,
tension rises a notch.
To give the presentation to our CMD is very difficult because he's the person who is always looking for new developments and he has got the brilliant taste of the fabric.
Looking at the fabrics,
he will be able to tell you whether the fabric is from the 180s or
200s, or it's from Baikonur or the Pashmina or the Kashmir.
The boss arrives.
His team has 30 minutes to convince and surprise him.
We are also not looking for only one category.
TechnoSmart can be one feature and we can develop many product categories under this.
Our best development in TechnoSmart.
TechnoSmart Next
I have synthetic dyes.
It's not wool,
it's a little bit.
Absolutely,
sir.
25-30%.
The Indian textile prince is now at the heart of the family business.
It is these woolen fibres that his family has worked on for a century that made him king.
Like any good sovereign,
Gautama Singhania has his court and his protocol.
This is the antechamber of power.
Behind this door,
the throne room,
has all the glory of this billionaire and his family.
I'd rather put up memories of...
pictures on my walls than put up,
you know,
paintings,
which have no meaning to me.
The Singhanias are an old family from the Rajasthan province.
They are part of the Mawari community,
merchants among the richest in the country.
When you were growing up,
did you always have this image in your head that you were one day going to be taking over this company?
Were you groomed for this role?
Yeah,
I think from childhood you've been trained for this,
that,
you know,
in our Mawari system,
you are trained to...
to get into the family business and you expected to do that.
So whether it was dinner conversations or weekend conversations,
a lot of conversations revolved around business,
so you sort of learnt that way.
Our Marwadi family all come from Rajasthan,
from a small part called Sheikh Hawat,
and therefore we're called Sheikh Hawati Marwadis.
And for some strange reason,
the Sheikh Hawati Marwadis have all gone out and become big businessmen.
A fair for business which seems alive in the Singhania family.
My elder daughter is very,
very keen on running the business.
She's been coming here since the age of five,
trying to attend meetings.
She walks around the office and asks around and is very inquisitive.
It's good,
but let's see.
She's very young.
A woman at the head of the group would be an earthquake in this world of men attached to their history and their traditions.
For the Mawaris,
it is family and community that take precedence.
At the end of the CEO's day,
Gautama Singhania likes to relax,
without slowing down the pace.
He built his own race circuit on his company's campus.
Total cost of the cars and the track,
nearly 250,000 euros.
This discipline that he wants to launch in India is called the drift.
It is the art of controlled skidding and engines that roar.
We want to promote the sport so we just do this maybe two or three times a year where we tell people come and drift you know it's not a category wise or anything of that sort it's just you know bring whatever you got and people have this enthusiasm to take out some adrenaline
and so they
Come and do it on the track.
Are you the godfather of drift in India?
I don't say godfather,
but I'm probably the only drifter from India.
Far from high-end textiles and suit jackets,
it is here that this speed demon gets his adrenaline rush.
This taste for danger fascinates the Indian media,
who are accustomed to the billionaire's escapades.
India who has passion for speed and who can afford this passion and he has four drifting cars and then Ferraris,
Lamborghinis,
the best of the cars.
Two years ago,
Gautama Singhania decided to treat himself to the thrill of a true automobile competition.
Despite
his responsibilities,
he has taken the time to travel the world to live out his dream and fly the colours of the Indian flag.
The entrance to the
ticket to this Sunday's sport event costs a million euros.
At that price,
the souvenir video looks like the trailer for an action film.
For his first year,
the novice finished fourth worldwide.
This evening,
he celebrates his season at this chic club in the center of Bombay,
where the owner himself remembers the scale of his exploits.
Having said that,
I have to tell you it's probably one of the most competitive forms of motorsport I have ever seen.
It's infinitely more competitive than Formula 1.
No more turnovers or associates.
Gautama Singhania,
the racer,
celebrates in style with a crown of admirers.
Ultra-ambitious megalomaniacs,
the Maharajas of today,
see themselves as the heroes of modern India.
But in the country of Gandhi,
where 40 million children still suffer from malnutrition,
some of these new Maharajas manage to avoid paying taxes.
India ranks number one in the world for tax evasion.
More than 500 billion euros are allegedly hidden abroad.
India's most flamboyant,
a willful defaulter.
How does a business baron who owes banks thousands of crores of rupees get to leave the country?
Now his passport has been revoked by the government.
The icon of these tax evaders is V.
Vijay Mallya,
the boss of Kingfisher Beverages,
nicknamed the Indian Richard Branson.
He is a fan of luxury and beautiful women,
and now he's on the run.
After having made his fortune in the alcohol business,
the party king wanted him to be
his own planes.
He launched an upscale airline as the Indian skies were already overloaded.
The rise in oil prices ended up sinking his dream and deepening his debt.
All of Vijay Mallya's Indian property was supposed to be put up for auction to pay his creditors.
Villas,
planes,
cars.
But several months after the billionaire's flight,
his collectible car still shined behind the windows of this building in New Delhi,
like a mockery to the tax office.
Using hidden cameras,
we discover dr malia's secret garage nice to meet you pleasure
40 gleaming luxury cars make up this great collectors a small museum you wouldn't drive those cars dr maria no no you would have what a driver and uh
How much do you think would this whole cost?
A year itself would be about
50 crores.
Right.
The mechanic tells us that there is another bigger warehouse in the south of the city.
city and no hint of a seizure to pay back his debts.
The company belongs to Dr.
Maria.
Yeah.
At the end of the day,
it is...
Yeah,
that's his...
That's still his toys.
He left these jewels behind when he took the road to exile,
or rather,
to his golden retirement.
we went to find him we traced him back to france to the cote d'azur just off cannes he's the owner of one of the most beautiful residences in the region on il saint marguerite also one of the most expensive his villa and its huge garden is estimated between 30 and 40 million euros for
the islands in
For the inhabitants,
the extravagant high roller is a normal resident,
but not an ordinary one.
He has managed to get himself a few privileges.
We know he has two big boats in the area.
He would have a nice apartment in Monaco.
I think he's fine on this side.
While this huge garden is his haven of peace,
Monaco is his stomping ground.
Parties that he organizes during the Formula One Grand Prix have remained in everyone's memories,
like this one three years ago,
because VJ Malja loves a party in all its excess.
Clément de Souza was his private DJ for 20 years.
These parties he lived from the inside.
I play for his parties in Monaco during the F1.
So that's when we are on the yacht.
He's got a huge
100-foot yacht.
He's flown me a couple of times in the past in his private jet because he decides sometimes last minute,
you know,
like I want to have a party.
And he actually has a full-fledged nightclub inside his villa in Goa.
I played for his
50th birthday,
which was a huge celebration in Goa.
Like,
Enrique Iglesias,
Lionel Richie all flew down to wish him and stuff like that.
Four days of non-stop events.
This party lifestyle stopped one year ago when the high roller fell with a crash.
When he left India,
he sought refuge in London.
So he went there.
Vijay Mallya has been a British resident for more than 20 years.
He was attracted to England and its tax system.
Today,
he takes advantage of its discretion.
Our request for an interview went unanswered.
The billionaire hides away behind the walls of his manor in North London.
But we finally caught sight of him last March,
when the Formula One season started again.
Vijay Mallya's little indulgence.
He couldn't resist the urge to show up with his new car in front of cameras from all over the world.
The exiled billionaire only comes out of his silence to talk about his favourite sport,
his passion.
The strategy is clear.
Mr Malia has done nothing wrong.
I do not owe one euro personally to any bank.
Kingfisher Airlines Limited unfortunately closed down the business and they try to hold me personally responsible.
You come home for face the justice of your country,
for example.
Why should I?
First of all,
there has to be...
A proper legal charge against me,
which there isn't,
all right?
Vijay Mallya lies without a hint of remorse.
A judicial procedure for non-payment was launched over a year ago,
and a few days after filming,
the king of the alcohol business was arrested by Scotland Yard for several hours.
He awaits extradition to India.
But the fall of Vijay Mallya does not frighten the Indian Novorij.
Ivan Lutra,
the young millionaire,
sees himself high in the rankings of India's largest fortunes,
those in the billions.
It is in London that we also find him,
in a bling-bling gold 4x4,
marketing his new application,
Bottle Pop.
London's the best market for Bottle Pop,
you know.
There's just too many people spending too much disposable income on bottles that they don't remember the next day,
including myself.
You go out and people will obviously be buying more and more champagne bottles with the sparklers because they do it,
the girls come to the tables and that's what they want,
they want people to show off.
It's a shallow society,
it's always a competition because everybody can see everybody but the app makes a commission whatever our clients spend,
so that's how we make money.
With Bottle Pop,
Evan can earn nearly €20,000 commission for each soiree.
This money,
which flows freely in London,
the European finance capital,
is what attracts more and more Indian fortunes here.
Hey,
Siva.
What's up,
man?
How are you?
Good,
Indian businessmen have taken over London like crazy,
you know.
Lakshmi Mittal,
he's one of the biggest residences in the area.
He's from India.
Tata is an Indian businessman.
He's the largest private employer in all of the UK.
An Indian company is the biggest private employer.
Evan spends a lot of time in London,
also to find new business ideas,
no matter where.
Tonight,
he has a meeting.
At a fairground with Stan,
a young French 17-year-old,
He is looking for funding for his project,
a virtual reality headset for medical students.
It teaches them how to operate in almost real conditions.
So if I'm wearing the headset,
what am I seeing?
I'm seeing a body next to me and this doctor who is operating on the body.
And you're searching and doing it and you see it and you look at the experience and through looking you learn.
You've got to have a number in your mind,
you've got to know how much money you need.
We're not going to say a huge amount because...
to start
80K pounds.
And where does the 80K pounds go?
80K pounds goes in salary.
For the young Frenchman,
this meeting is very important for the funding of his project.
The guy who makes all the books,
the guy who makes all the smart classes.
It's very good that he has managed to do it.
He is 20 years old and he already has a lot of money.
He is already very famous on social media.
We can see that,
etc.
Ivan is seduced by the idea.
He suggests they meet again quickly.
I have some friends in London.
We have a fund that's just investing in VR companies.
That's why I actually had the meeting with you.
We're looking for deals all the time,
so if you can send me a pitch deck,
it doesn't matter where you meet them,
it doesn't matter what's in their brains.
You could meet me in a fucking toilet,
but if you make me a million dollars,
I'll sign up right now.
A few weeks later,
Ivan will invest 580,000 euros in the young Frenchman's start-up.
The millionaire does not merely want to reign supreme in India.
but to count,
to be known and to be recognized around the world.
And for that,
he multiplies his trips,
but also his parties,
an essential component of his image.
24 hours later,
we find him in Berlin,
in a luxury car,
in direction to the most chic area of the German capital.
This evening,
Ivan has a meeting in a presidential suite,
which costs 2,700 euros a night.
With other millionaires under the age of 25 like him,
exclusively men.
Chinese,
Germans,
Russians or Indians,
they are all part of the rich kids of Instagram.
The world's golden youth who display themselves on social media.
This group is the creme de la creme of the spoiled children of the internet.
Trash videos,
nefarious photos,
these unhibited nouveau riche kids like to take center stage online.
They have more money than you,
and this is what they do,
is their welcome message on Instagram.
You can see their VIP trips,
their passion for parties,
luxury and excess of all kinds.
Ivan Lutra is one of the most active rich kids on social media.
In just a few years,
he has become one of the stars of the group.
With uninhibited and materialistic discourse bordering crudeness.
We have to cheer.
I'm your host tonight.
We do have a lot of fun.
All the best,
Evan.
Great.
Cheers.
I always say work smart,
play hard.
I never say to work hard.
It's always about doing the right thing.
A lot of people do a lot of hard work,
labor,
but they don't achieve anything in life.
A lot of people can make one phone call and get a million bucks in the bank.
If you want to spend money like we do,
you can't be stupid.
Stupid people don't make money.
Stupid people are broke.
So if people have money,
they're probably smart.
Tonight,
Ivan's objective is to flash his cash on social media and to broaden his community of fans.
I mean,
I have like 200,000 followers.
They want to see.
You know,
so you've got to give them good content.
Cheers
Cheers to everybody
The meal sprinkled with champagne is quickly wolfed down because it is in this hip nightclub that the partygoers will give it their all.
Indians love gold.
All Indians love gold.
That's how it is.
If you see Indians,
they must have gold like this.
Jewelry,
champagne and girls.
Tonight,
the apprentice billionaires will lift all the clichés to feed their Instagram accounts.
Play in your mouth.
The cost of the soirée will remain confidential,
but the young high rollers spend sometimes up to 100,000 euros per night.
If you are sure of success,
that gives you more success.
Thanks to contacts wrapped up in a box or elsewhere,
Ivan Lutra has invested in more than 40 businesses all over the world.
These new Indian Maharajas are only at the beginning of their reigns.
Next year,
some 20 new billionaires are expected to boost India's place in the rankings of the world's biggest fortunes.